Guide to the Samuel Halperin Puck and Judge cartoon collection, 1879-1903 MS2121
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Illustrations from "Puck", 1879-1903; MS2121 Series 1; 2 Linear feet
  - "The Duty That Lies Near."Puck.-"The new parks are a good thing, Mr. Grace, but suppose we begin by making 'breathing-places of these dirty streets!", undated (Box 3, Folder 182)
  - "EASTER.", undated (Box 3, Folder 183)
  - "The Elephant's Revenge.", undated (Box 3, Folder 184)
  - "Excelsior Ben.", undated (Box 3, Folder 185)
  - "The European Monarchs' Peace-Meeting.""Sheep huddle together when the storm is coming."-Old Proverb., undated (Box 3, Folder 186)
  - "A Fantasia on the Fall Fashions."(2 copies), undated (Box 3, Folder 187)
  - "The Fate of a Flirt."A Summer Romance., undated (Box 3, Folder 188)
  - "15-14-13.-The Great American Puzzle.", undated (Box 3, Folder 189)
  - "Freaks of Fashion.", undated (Box 3, Folder 190)
  - "`French Flats' in New York.", undated (Box 3, Folder 191)
  - "A Good Canvas, a Rotten Boat, and a Bad Passenger.", undated (Box 3, Folder 192)
  - "Gotham's Gospel Needs."Why Send Our Missionaries to Afric's Sunny Fountains? Let Them Stay Here and Labor Among the Barbarous Tribes of the Metropolis.", undated (Box 3, Folder 193)
  - William Tecumseh Sherman,"The Great General of Our Small Army.", undated (Box 3, Folder 194)
  - "Hans and His Chums.", undated (Box 3, Folder 195)
  - "A Hard Road to Travel."Arthur:-"If the New York `Boys' would only drop off, I might stand a chance to get there!", undated (Box 3, Folder 196)
  - "Harold Witherbee's Triumph- A Story of Adventure in New Jersey.", undated (Box 3, Folder 197)
  - "He Courts the Mother and Means the Daughter.", undated (Box 3, Folder 198)
  - "He Goes Up Like a Rocket, And He Will Come Down Like a Stick!", undated (Box 3, Folder 199)
  - "His Opinion.", undated (Box 3, Folder 200)
  - "How the Bottom Fell Out of Pussy's Plan.", undated (Box 3, Folder 201)
  - "In Line at Last.", undated (Box 3, Folder 202)
  - "In Little Boy Land.", undated (Box 3, Folder 203)
  - "In the Heyday of Youth."Uncle Ephriam.-Young Bige Tompkins is goin; ter teach the Burdock school, an' Lazarus Mickle is takin' a daily paper, an' Peg Barclow's boy is writin' the Corncob Corners items fer the Frogeye Bulwark of Liberty.Uncle Ebenezer.-Beats all! It gits plainer every day that this is truly the "young man's age.", undated (Box 3, Folder 204)
  - "Intoxicated With His Own Glory."His Supports are Giving Way-Can He Stand Alone?, undated (Box 3, Folder 205)
  - "The Irish Land Question.", undated (Box 3, Folder 206)
  - "The Irrestible Magnet.-A Counter Attraction to New Year's Good Resolves.", undated (Box 3, Folder 207)
  - "Is Marriage a Failure?"Yes; in this case., undated (Box 3, Folder 208)
  - "Jayson's Visit to the Track.", undated (Box 3, Folder 209)
  - "Keeping Up With the Times.- The Progressive Tramp Takes to the Wheel.", undated (Box 3, Folder 210)
  - "The Last Effort.", undated (Box 3, Folder 211)
  - "Left Out."Schurz and Evarts:-"Aren't you going to provide for before you go?"Hayes:-"You two are clever enough to provide for yourselves!", undated (Box 3, Folder 212)
  - "Let Them Have it All, and Be Done With It.", undated (Box 3, Folder 213)
  - "A Little Common Sense for the Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children.", undated (Box 3, Folder 214)
  - "A Long-Felt Want Supplied- Puck's Hand-Book of Etiquette for 'Help.' ", undated (Box 3, Folder 215)
  - "Marrying For Fun.", undated (Box 3, Folder 216)
  - "Mischievous Moles."The Grand Old Gardener Gladstone and His Grubbed-Up Bed., undated (Box 3, Folder 217)
  - "MISSED!""No turkey for you this year, Benjamin!", undated (Box 3, Folder 218)
  - "Mr. Bergh's Dual Nature.", undated (Box 3, Folder 219)
  - "Mr. Fox's Bad Break."And how it brought Christmas joy to Bunnysville., undated (Box 3, Folder 220)
  - "The Mode and the Martyrs.", undated (Box 3, Folder 221)
  - "The Modern Builder.", undated (Box 3, Folder 222)
  - "The Monopoly Pharaohs Building Their Tombs.""The Mausoleums of Vanderbilt and Gould, when finished, will surpass anything ever yet seen."-Exchange., undated (Box 3, Folder 223)
  - "Moving Day in New York at Hand.-The Squatters Must Go!", undated (Box 4, Folder 224)
  - "The Murderous Policy of the `L' Roads.", undated (Box 4, Folder 225)
  - "The Naughtiness of the Noisy Newton and the Perplexity of the Peaceful Potter.""Please go away, Mr. Newton! This Church has gone out of the Martyr Business!", undated (Box 4, Folder 226)
  - "Needle and Pin Money.", undated (Box 4, Folder 227)
  - "A Never Ending `Job.' "Puck.-Gentlemen, it seems to me you have few workmen for such a big bridge.BROOKLYN BRIDGE DIRECTORS.-Well, you see, we are waiting for more "steel!", undated (Box 4, Folder 228)
  - "The New Favorite.", undated (Box 4, Folder 229)
  - "A New Version of an Old Story.""Goon": Are you in earnest, Col. Crockett? Then don't shoot- I'll come down for Eighty Millions!", undated (Box 4, Folder 230)
  - "A New Year's Present to Uncle Sam.", undated (Box 4, Folder 231)
  - "New York's Dirt and the Way to Get Rid of It."The Citizens Must Literally Take it Into Their Own Hands., undated (Box 4, Folder 232)
  - "A New Yorker's Visit to Maine."He Observes the Practical Working of the Great Total Abstinence Idea., undated (Box 4, Folder 233)
  - "The Newly Elected Board of Aldermen of the Metropolis.", undated (Box 4, Folder 234)
  - O'Donovon Rossa's Shooting-Gallery for Irish Dynamiters."He Lets Them Have the Fun, While He Takes the Cash., undated (Box 4, Folder 235)
  - "Old Thursday.", undated (Box 4, Folder 236)
  - "The Only Form of Trial that Would Satisfy the Chicago Anarchists- A Trial by a Court of Their Peers.", undated (Box 4, Folder 237)
  - "The Opposition Tabernacles."BROTHER TAYLOR TO BROTHER TALMADGE:- People who live in Brooklyn houses shouldn't throw stones!, undated (Box 4, Folder 238)
  - "`Our Congressman'- Past and Present.", undated (Box 4, Folder 239)
  - "Our False Prophet.""Cast Off the Old Parties and Follow Me! I'm the Only and Original Jacobs!", undated (Box 4, Folder 240)
  - "Our Local Snake-Charmer."They Had to Come Out when He Played on the Investigation Pipe., undated (Box 4, Folder 241)
  - "Our Religious Weeklies.", undated (Box 4, Folder 242)
  - "Paper Foundations. Banking On a Friendly Basis." / "The British Lion Thinks He Will Remain in Cabul." (We think so too.), undated (Box 4, Folder 243)
  - "Patent-Medicines.", undated (Box 4, Folder 244)
  - "The Patient Private Citizen."He can Smile and Smile, and be a Victim still., undated (Box 4, Folder 245)
  - "The Pet of the Monopolists.", undated (Box 4, Folder 246)
  - "A Picture for the Foes of Sunday Concerts."The Clergyman's Leisure and the Poor Man's Holiday.", undated (Box 4, Folder 247)
  - "Political Leap-Year - An Attack on the Workingman."But he had better look out, for she is a clinger, and she has a large and growing family to support. What's the matter with the little girl around the corner?, undated (Box 4, Folder 248)
  - "The Presidential Donkey-Party.", undated (Box 4, Folder 249)
  - "Press Rumors About Arthur.", undated (Box 4, Folder 250)
  - "Puck's Life of Garfield.", undated (Box 4, Folder 251)
  - "Puck's Life of General Hancock.", undated (Box 4, Folder 252)
  - "Puck's Little Suggestion to the Royal Targets of Europe- Try the Dummy Plan.", undated (Box 4, Folder 253)
  - "Puck's Moral Tales.-No. IV"The Tale of a Man who Investigated the "Drop-a-Nickel" Machines in the Broadway Bar-rooms., undated (Box 4, Folder 254)
  - "Puck's Revised Library of `Juvenile Fiction.' "Designed to Suit the Taste of the Rising Generation., undated (Box 4, Folder 255)
  - "Puck: `Your man of snow is big to-day, Under summer's sun he'll melt away.' ", undated (Box 4, Folder 256)
  - "The Republican Dalilah stealthily deprives the Democratic Sampson of his Strength." (2 copies), undated (Box 4, Folder 257)
  - "The Revised Bible Boom.", undated (Box 4, Folder 258)
  - "The `Revolt Against Cleveland' Industry."Forthcoming Extracts from the Tribune, Predicted by Puck., undated (Box 4, Folder 259)
  - "Ruinous City Notions.", undated (Box 4, Folder 260)
  - "Russian Freedom.", undated (Box 4, Folder 261)
  - "A Sad Mistake.", undated (Box 4, Folder 262)
  - "The Salesman's Snares for His Annual Victims.", undated (Box 4, Folder 263)
  - "Sarah Bernhardt, the Modern Rizpah, Protecting Her Son From Clerical Vultures."[A little Variation on M. Becker's Famous Picture.], undated (Box 4, Folder 264)
  - "`Sassiety' at the Sea."Uncle Hayseed's Chowder Party Blunders on Our Exclusive Beach, and is Edified., undated (Box 4, Folder 265)
  - "Scientific Testimony- Showing How it Acts on the Average Juryman.", undated (Box 4, Folder 266)
  - "The Sensation-Sermon Mania."Old-Style Christian:-"Where, oh, where can I go to hear a little plain, everyday religion preached?", undated (Box 4, Folder 267)
  - "Sherman on the Road.", undated (Box 4, Folder 268)
  - "Shoemaker, Stick to Your Last;"Or, An Old Adage Substantiated.", undated (Box 4, Folder 269)
  - "Slaves of the Trains; or, One of the Beauties of Living Out of Town!", undated (Box 4, Folder 270)
  - "A Stay Out of Proceedings."The Foot of Monopoly - and the Hand of Cleveland., undated (Box 4, Folder 271)
  - "A Stylish `Turnout.' " (2 copies), undated (Box 4, Folder 272)
  - "`Sunday-School Politicians' - And the Other Kind."A Tribune Definition Illustrated., undated (Box 4, Folder 273)
  - "Tempora Mutantur, etc." The Sunday Afternoon of Our Great Religious Reformer / The Sunday Afternoon of Our Temperance Hypocrite.", undated (Box 4, Folder 274)
  - "Ten Minutes for Refreshments and Divorce!"Our Suggestion.- A Divorce Court in Every Railroad Depot in Chicago! Time Saved, and Everybody Happy!", undated (Box 4, Folder 275)
  - "Teresina Tua."The Violin Fairy., undated (Box 4, Folder 276)
  - "Their Little Funeral.", undated (Box 4, Folder 277)
  - "There is Still a Future for the Ex-Senator.", undated (Box 4, Folder 278)
  - "The Transformation of Nuisances.- From Dive-Keepers to Temperance Apostles.", undated (Box 4, Folder 279)
  - "The Transfusion of Blood.- May the Operation Prove to be a Success!", undated (Box 4, Folder 280)
  - "A Trapper Trapped; or, a Wonderful Invention, and How its Value Was Proven.", undated (Box 4, Folder 281)
  - "Uncle Sam's Method Recommended to European Despots: Cover Not a Boiling Pot.", undated (Box 4, Folder 282)
  - "The Unsuccessful Alchemist- Trying to Make Political Gold for the Blaine Out of Anti-Cleveland Dross.", undated (Box 4, Folder 283)
  - "Wanted, a Leader! - The Labor-Agitation Orchestra on the Go-As-You-Please Plan.", undated (Box 4, Folder 284)
  - "Welcome, Talmage!", undated (Box 4, Folder 285)
  - "When Brute Meets Brute Then Comes the Applause of Curs.", undated (Box 4, Folder 286)
  - "Why Not? - Glove-Fights as a Church Fair Attraction!" (2 copies), undated (Box 4, Folder 287)
  - "Why Will Our Poor Indulge in the Extravagance of Costly Funerals?", undated (Box 4, Folder 288)
  - "A Windy Day on the Midway.", undated (Box 4, Folder 289)
  - "Winter Resorts.", undated (Box 4, Folder 290)
  - "A Wrestle With Rum; Or, How George Softdrinks Won His Bride.", undated (Box 4, Folder 291)
  - "Yesterday an Infuriated Mob Almost Lynched a Man Who Looked Like Jay Gould.", undated (Box 4, Folder 292)
  - "Ye Brave Knight Comes to Ye Rescue of Ye Prisoned Mayde.", undated (Box 4, Folder 293)
  - "A Dangerous American Institution-The Free and Untrammeled Revolver.", 1870 ca.-1880 ca. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - "You May Bark! But Don't Dare To Bite!", 12/03/1879 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - "Out Of The Darkness. Will the Cloud of Bossism Again Enfold Brooklyn?", 1880 ca. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - "A Hint For An Unobjectionable Monopoly", 1880 ca. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - "Gathering Autumn Leaves.", 1880 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - "Our Top-Heavy Navy. A Roost For Useless Birds.", 02/23/1881 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - "No interference with 'gentlemen's' amusements, you know!", 06/29/1881 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - "The Political Sutler.", 1882 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - "The Carrion Crow In The Eagle's Nest.", 1882 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - "In Memoriam-Leopold Damrosch.", 1885 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - "After The Mexican War Veterans Are Pensioned-There Are A Few Other Humble Claimants Who Are Quite Ready To March On The Treasury.", 1885 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - "It Works Both Ways.", 11/25/1885 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - "A Hint To A Long-Suffering People.", 09/22/1886 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    General note
    Full text on illustration: "A Hint To A Long-Suffering People. When Plumbers are fighting each other, oh, then Is a possible chance for respectable men; Let us hang them together, both 'Union' and 'Rats,' And hope for the fate of the Kilkenny cats."
  - "Johnny's Ambitions, And How They Were Not Realized.", 1887 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - "A Political Mother-Goose Melody.", 1888 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    Full text on illustration: "A Political Mother-Goose Melody. Pussy's in the Well! Who Put Her In? - We Regret to Say: 'T was the Naughty Republi-kin. Who'll Come Forward and Take Out the Cat? - 'Why, I Will, with Pleasure,' Says the Good Democrat."
  - "A Heavy Load To Carry.", 06/27/1888 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - "In The Political Arena.-The Biggest Bag Wins.", 11/28/1888 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - "The Metropolitan Museum.", 01/02/1889 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    Full text on illustration: "The Metropolitan Museum. 'It is intended as much for the humblest artisan as for the most refined lover of the fine arts.'-Henry G. Marquand' And this is how the workingman enjoys the Museum on his only day of liberty.-Puck."
  - "At It Again. Uncle Sam (to N.Y. Sensation Press).-Calm down, Sonny-you couldn't kill the World's Fair, and you can't scare me!", 06/14/1893 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - "Jealousy Makes Him Ridiculous. He Vents His Spite Against The Chicago Fair Because It Excels His Own Effort Of 1889.", 07/26/1893 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - "A Revelation In Revolutions. Uncle Sam.-Well! Well! You boys have at last had a revolution which will help the whole world.", 11/25/1903 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - "A Tough Job For The Atlas Of The Labor World. Henry George.- If you fellows up there don't keep quiet, I shall have to drop the whole thing!", undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - "Free America.", undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
    Full text on illustration: "Free America. Chorus of Skilled Foreigners.-why are we not allowed to land, when those over there are received with open arms? Official-The law lets them fellers in because they didn't come over under contract; an'it keep you out because you did."
  - "In Danger.", undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - "Expensive Blowing In Congress. Come, ye gas-bags, both blue and gray,-Start yourselves on your homeward way.", undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Unknown Title, illustration of assemblyman dancing on New York., 05/11/1887 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    Text on illustration: "Oh, I am a rural assembyman, From Wayback County fair, With no conscience at all, and one ounce of brains, And the hayseed in my hair. And I dance all over New York's proud town, With a foot as heavy as Fate; I levy her taxes and pocket my bribes, And New York must pay the freight."
  - "A Thanksgiving Picture, With Puck's Compliments.", 1879 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - "Our Navy.", 02/11/1880 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - "Down With The Lotteries!", 1880 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - "Positively Last Awakening Of The Democratic Rip Van Winkle,-'Don't leave me here for another twenty years!' ", 1880 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - "The Decadence Of The World Of Menlo Park.-From The Phonograph To Polyform.", 1880 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - "Between Two Rogues.", 04/20/1881 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - "Cut-Throat Business In Wall Street.-How The Inexperienced Lose Their Heads.", 09/07/1881 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - "Reason Against Reason.", 1882 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - "Licensed Wreckers.-In The Hands Of The Receivers.", 1882 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - "The Modern Prometheus.", 1882 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    Full text on illustration: "The Modern Prometheus. [Prometheus was Condemned to be Bound to a Rock, where, until Delivered from his Painful Confinement by Hercules, a Bird of Prey was to Feed upon his Liver.]"
  - "Men May Come, And Men May Go; But The Work Of Reform Shall Go On Forever.", 1884 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - "Noxious Growths In Liberty's Grounds.", 1885 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    Full text on illustration: "Noxious Growths In Libery's Grounds. Uncle Sam.-Hello, Puck, are you 'up a tree'? - - Puck.-No, but you will be if you don't clear this stuff out pretty soon!"
  - "The Night Before Christmas-An Unnecessary Call.", 1887 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    Full text on illustration: "The Night Before Christmas-An Unnecessary Call. Santa Claus.-This is getting to be too extravagant for me! I guess I'll go where I'm more needed."
  - "Between Slavery And Starvation.", 10/26/1887 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - "Rise In The Value Of The Hayseed Legislator.", 1888 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - "Protection For American Actors-Those Who Need It. And Those Who Don't.", 1889 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - "Thanksgiving 1903", MS2121 Series 1 (Flat box 16, Folder 1)
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Transfer from the Luther Brady Art Gallery June 28, 2022 (Accession 2022.030)
  - "Christmas 1903", MS2121 Series 1 (Flat box 16, Folder 2)
    Transfer from the Luther Brady Art Gallery June 27, 2022 (Accession 2022.030)
  - "The David and Golitah Of Today.-And Goliath Is Bound To Get The Worst Of It.", undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - "The Gentler Sex-Charity For The Drunken Brother. Contempt For The Unfortunate Sister.", undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - "The Evolution Of The Anarchist.", undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - "A Revery.", undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - "Escaping From The Old Shell.", undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - "The Two Philanthropists. 'Don't fret, Uncle Sam, we only want to make a bigger man of you!' ", undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - "For The Favored Few.", undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    Full text on illustration: "For The Favored Few. 'These trusts are the natural offspring of a market artificially restricted.'-Grover Cleveland, Letter of Acceptance."
  - "The Bugaboo Of Congres.", undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
    Full text on illustration: "The Bugaboo Of Congress. The Reason Why We Cannot Expect Legislation On The Dynamite Question."
  - "The Modern Wandering Jew.", undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
    Full text on illustration: "The Modern Wandering Jew. A fated wanderer, his way he wends, Driven here and there by many selfish friends; Where'er he goes, sign of a people's wrath, The Curse of the Third Term still haunts his path."
  - "He Won't Have It.", undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
    Full text on illustration: "He Won't Have It. The Greatest Living Mis-Statesman.-Trusts are largely private affairs. The Greatest Living Carnegie.-The public may regard Trusts with serene confidence. Uncle Sam.-Silence, you apologists for Robbery! or I'll give you a dose of 'Triumphant Democracy' that you won't like!"
  - "The Last Resort.-Let The Democrats Throw Their 'Jonah' Overboard.", undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - "The Philadelphia Physician-Factory.", undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - "A Family Party.-The 200th Birthday Of The Healthiest of Uncle Sam's Adopted Children.", undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - "The Wake Over The Remains Of The Democratic Party.", undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - "Working On The Sympathies Of The Jury.", undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
    Full text on illustration: "Working On The Sympathies Of The Jury. This Sort of Thing has Gone So Far Already, that We Might as Well Do the Family Tableau Business Up in Systematic Style, for the Benefit of out Distinguished Criminals."
  - "The Slave Market Of Today. 'Going-going-lower-lower!' ", undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - "Grand Presidential Auction-Sale For The Year 1888.", undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - "Welcome To All!", undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
    Full text on illustration: "Welcom to All! 'We may safely say that the present influx of immigration to the United States is something unprecedented in our generation.'-N.Y. Statistical Review."
  - "This Is What The 'Freedom Of Worship' Bill Means.-Can We Hold The Evil In Check?", undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - "Thanksgiving.", undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Full text on illustration: Thanksgiving. Uncle Sam.-"Well, we seem to be getting along a little bettern than the rest of the world, and if we can't be thankful for all that we have, we may at least be thankful that thre are som things which we haven't.' "
  - "A Merry Christmas To All!", undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - "Too Many Leaders.", undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - "Quackery-Medical Minstrels Performing For The Benefit O Their Former Patients-No Other Dead-Heads Admitted.", undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - "Beauties Of The Installment Plan.", undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - "Let Us Have Peace, Now A President's Elected.", undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    Full text on illustration: "Let Us Have Peace, Now A President's Elected. Chorus of Invisibles.-But Where are his Features to be detected?"
  - "All The Difference.", undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
    Full text on illustration: "All The Difference. East-Keeping Withing The Law. West-Defying The Law."
  - "Playing The Trojan Horse Trick On The Treasury.", undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
    Full text on illustration: "Puck.-Aha! I'll let the people know that the pension-sharks are trying to make a stalking-horse of the Grand Army Organization!"
  - "The Mephistopheles Of To-day - Honest Labor's Tempation.", undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - "The Republican Idea Of Protection", undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
    Full text on illustration: "The Republican Idea Of Protection - A High Tariff on the Monopolist's Wares, Free Entrance for Pauper Labor, and a Lock-Out for the American Wrokingman."
  - "Let Us Have A Good Bankruptcy Law, As A Protection Against The 'Preferred Creditor' Swindle.", undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - "Some 'Children' Of The Present Day.", undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
    Full text on illustration: "Some 'Children' Of The Present Day. Santa Claus.-'Well, They Don't Seem To Have Much Use For Me! They're Like A Lot Of Little Old Men And Women! If They're Going To Get Like, This, I May As Well Retire From Business!' "
  - Unknown Title, Depiction of The World's International Cotton Centennial Exposition from Dec. 1, 1884 to May 31, 1885., 1884-1885 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    Full text on illustration: "Now Peace hath done her perfect work-serene, Loyal and beautiful, the Southern queen Bids all the wide world welcome to her door, Where Industry has spread a varied store, Where the white splendor of her heaping bales Answers the snow of crowding foreign sales- Wise sister, blessed be thy welcoming hand, Stretched to Republics of the tropic land!"
  - The Adopted Child, 101/25/1882; Series 1 (Box 11, Item 14)
    Scope and Contents
    "Faith, and it's on the bottle we'll bring it up - and ourselves, too!"
  - Pat's Double Burden, 12/22/1880; Series 1 (Box 11, Item 15)
  - The next reception of the Chinese Embassy The Washington Hog will not take them by surprise again, undated; Series 1 (Box 11, Item 16)
  - The Rest Question, undated; Series 1 (Flat box 15, Item 3)
    Text on document "Puck to Capitalist: -"Why not build little $1000 Cottages and let them to our Laboring Classes at $12 a mounth, so that they may breathe pure air - it wold be a paying investment?" Capitalists: -"My dear fellow- they wouldn't live in them if I did. Even if they had a lodge oer a Stable or a Gin mill, they won't leave the city!"
  - European Notions of American Manners and Customs, undated; Series 1 (Flat box 15, Item 4)
  - The Last Resort for the Crowned heads. - Go West!", undated; Series 1 (Flat box 15, Item 5)